Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/jeff-norte-23a39623 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Credit Analysis
Commercial Lending
Credit

Certifications
CPA

Jeff Norte

Chief Credit Officer at Capital Farm Credit Austin, Texas Area

Summary

Jeff Norte is the Chief Credit Officer of Capital Farm Credit. Jeff has over 30 years of experience in banking. He joined Capital Farm Credit (CFC) in September 2010, and currently oversees all credit teams, special assets group, enterprise risk management, appraisal, project management and strategic planning at the Associations. Prior to joining CFC, he spent five years at CoBank in Corporate AgriBusiness and International Trade Finance. Prior to CoBank, he spent 14 years as a Bank Regulator with the FDIC and two years working for a large bank in Kansas City. Jeff also has previous experience as an Auditor and is a CPA. He has a BS in Accounting from Mid America Nazarene University and a Masters in Business Administration from Concordia University, Austin, Texas. Jeff has also served in the Armed Forces (Army) and currently serves on credit and risk committees for the Farm Credit System. He, his wife, and two daughters enjoy spending time at their ranch outside Austin with their horses.

Experience

Capital Farm Credit
Chief Credit Officer
September 2010 - Present (9 years 11 months)

Oversee credit underwriting and structuring team for large corporate agribusiness borrowers.

CoBank

Senior Credit Manager June 2005 - September 2010 (5 years 4 months)

Managed credit team for \$8Bn corporate agribusiness accounts, as well as \$4Bn international trade finance.

Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC)
Regional Accountant
June 1991 - May 2005 (14 years)

Page 1 of 2

Describe your position

Education

Concordia University-Austin

Master of Business Administration (M.B.A.) · (2012 - 2014)

University of Colorado at Boulder Graduate Degree in Banking · (1997 - 1999)

MidAmerica Nazarene University BS, Accounting · (1987 - 1991)

Medford Senior HS · (1979 - 1982)